Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Episodes, 1988-1991; Series I
  - Third Season
    - Episode 212, 1989; 1 (Box 40)
      The episode includes: Namibia Watch: United Nations calls for confinement of South African troops for seventy-two hours; profile of Archbishop Desmond Tutu; the truth behind the filming of Red Scorpion; covering the coverage, William F. Buckley's Firing Line.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 40D)
    - Episode 213, 1989; 1 (Box 41)
      The episode includes: sanctions busting; Namibia update: London Telegraph releases fresh evidence; assassination of David Webster; Albie Sachs' documentary on war-torn Mozambique, The Deeper Image.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 41D)
  - Fourth Season
    - Episode 301, 1989; 1 (Box 42)
      The episode includes: David Webster funeral investigation; political killings in South Africa; high level United Nations investigation on SWAPO executions; South African political cartoonist Jonathan Shapiro, singer Michelle Shocked donates her South African record royalties to the ANC.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 42D)
    - Episode 302, 1989; 1 (Box 43)
      The episode includes: the Kellogg's boycott; P.W. Botha apologizes to Margaret Thatcher for violated arms embargo; Laura Branigan plays Sun City for a second time; analysis of Anglo-American takeover bid.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 43D)
    - Episode 303, 1989; 1 (Box 44)
      The episode includes: peace through pressure, South African religious leaders on Capitol Hill; Mozambique; investigation into sanctions busting; Lucky Dube, South Africa's leading reggae star.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 44D)
    - Episode 304, 1989; 1 (Box 45)
      The episode includes: David Seftel (?): medicine on the frontline; Beyers Naudé profile; David Turnley, American photographer expelled from South Africa.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 45D)
    - Episode 305, 1989; 1 (Box 46)
      The episode includes: journalism in Black townships; uprooting poverty in South Africa; Mapantsula, South Africa's version of the film The Harder They Come.
    - Episode 306, 1989; 1 (Box 47)
      The episode includes: Reverend Frank Chikane, head of South African Council of Churches (SACC), is poisoned; tension continues in Natal; Soweto uprising of June 16, 1976, is commemorated.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 47D)
    - Episode 307, 1989; 1 (Box 48)
      The episode includes: Soweto Day commemorated in South Africa and the United States; report on the Koevoet unit of the Nambian Police; Izulu dance troupe.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 48D)
    - Episode 308, 1989; 1 (Box 49)
      The episode includes: peace in Angola, an analysis; South Africa sentences fourteen of the Upington 26 to death; Commodores cancel plans to play Sun City resort; Lorraine Klaasen, South African singer, visits New York City.
    - Episode 309, 1989; 1 (Box 50)
      The episode includes: ANC video facility in South Africa, exclusive report; congress lobbied by South Africa, investigative report; Amnesty International concert in Harare, Zimbabwe, in late 1988.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 50D)
    - Episode 310, 1989; 1 (Box 51)
      The episode includes: Mandela-Botha meeting, Mandela release rumors; Albertina Sisulu's American visit; De Klerk's five-year plan; unrest in Bophuthatswana.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 51D)
    - Episode 311, 1989; 1 (Box 52)
      The episode includes: investigative report on the right-wing religious community and South Africa; background report on Mandela's potential release; South Africans are the bad guys in Lethal Weapon 2; profile of Hugh Masakela.
      The tape begins with content already in progress.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 52D)
    - Episode 312, 1989; 1 (Box 53)
      The episode includes: De Klerk declines invitation to Washington D.C.; largest white South African delegation ever meets with ANC leaders in Zambia; Mozambique report: the war continues; interview with Zephania Mothopeng, president of the Pan-Africanist Council.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 53D)
  - First Season (National)
    - Episode N101, 1989 August 2; 1 (Box 54)
      The episode includes: three day conference of the Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU) in Johannesburg, what the workers want and why; Inside South Africa, South Africa's answer to South Africa Now; "South Africa and the Bomb," investigative report on South Africa's nuclear capacity; the world beat of Johnny Clegg and Savuka.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 54D)
    - Episode N102, 1989 August 9; 1 (Box 55)
      The episode includes: Hospital Defiance Campaign for Equal Health Care in South Africa; Out of Sight, Out of Mind, an Irish documentary on South African media censorship; South Africa church groups targeted, poison gas attack at South African Council of Churches (SACC) conference; UNITA violates Angolan ceasefire.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 55D)
    - Episode N103, 1989 August 16; 1 (Box 56)
      The episode includes: P.W. Botha resigns, analysis of situation by Tom Lodge, political analyst; National Women's Day commemorates the anniversary of 1956 pass law protest; report on Afrocentricity and how it relates to the struggle for liberation in South Africa; interview with Naomi Tutu regarding her book about her father, the Archbishop.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 56D)
    - Episode N104, 1989 August 23; 1 (Box 57)
      The episode includes: Defiance Campaign continues; South African schools in crisis; Lawaaikamp/St. Paul sister cities project, averting forced removal; Jonas Gwangwa, jazz musician.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 57D)
    - Episode N105, 1989 August 30; 1 (Box 58)
      The episode includes: Defiance Campaign brings more repression, civil disobedience in South Africa; preview of South Africa elections on September 6: who is running and what the people think; apartheid supported by corporate clout: a look ahead to the United Nations conference in Geneva; Arthur Ashe leads campaign against 1990 tennis tournaments in South Africa.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 58D)
    - Episode N106, 1989 September 6; 1 (Box 59)
      The episode includes: Defiance Campaign escalates to protest September 6 elections; Out of Sight, Out of Mind documentary examines media censorship inside South Africa; South Africa's Conservative Party linked to United States right-wing factions; British rappers speak out against apartheid in Beyond the 16th Parallel.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 59D)
    - Episode N107, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 60)
      The episode includes: special election edition: is the political climate changing? A panel discussion by political analysts; Evangelical Lutheran Church in America votes to divest; South African workers through the lens of photographer David Lurie.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 60D)
    - Episode N108, 1989 September 20; 1; videotape (1") (Box 61)
      The episode includes: Namibia Watch: SWAPO President Sam Nujoma returns to Namibia after thirty years of exile; Anton Lubowski, SWAPO leader, assassinated in Namibia; oil and apartheid, South Africa's secret oil trade; Tony Bird, African folksinger.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 61D)
    - Episode N109, 1989 September 27; 1 (Box 62)
      The episode includes: appeal granted to Upington 14; corporate clout: United Nations Transnationals conference; Angola, victims of war; A Dry White Season, the acclaimed major motion picture
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 62D)
    - Episode N110, 1989 October 4; 1 (Box 63)
      The episode includes: Angola update: Savimbi and Van Dunem Loy to visit the United States; covering the coverage: the Mass Democratic Movement is called "shadowy" by New York Times correspondent; South Africa funded and sponsored television series, Shaka Zulu, returns to prime time; Ziggy Marley plays a benefit for Namibia.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 63D)
    - Episode N111, 1989 October 11; 1 (Box 64)
      The episode includes: United States government discusses whether sanctions should be imposed; Savimbi meets with Bush administration; South African military, where do the weapons come from; the truth behind The Gods Must Be Crazy Part 2.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 64D)
    - Episode N112, 1989 October 18; 1 (Box 65)
      The episode includes: Sisulu's release and what it means for the future of South Africa; Africa South magazine; South African draft resisters speak out; folksinger Phranc sings out against apartheid.
      - Duplicating master for N112, N113, and N201, 1 (Box 65D)
    - Episode N113, 1989 October 25; 1 (Box 66)
      The episode includes: Walter Sisulu's homecoming, exclusive interview; banks reschedule South African debt; profile of TransAfrica, Randall Robinson commentary; A World Apart is released on home video.
      - Duplicating master for N112, N113, and N201, 1 (Box 65D)
  - Second Season (National)
    - Episode N201, 1989 November 1; 1 (Box 67)
      The episode includes: Namibia, the long road to independence, countdown to elections; largest official ANC rally in South Africa in twenty-five years; South Africa's partnership with Israel to produce nuclear weapons; Randall Robinson commentary on Angola.
      - Duplicating master for N112, N113, and N201, 1 (Box 65D)
    - Episode N202, 1989 November 8; 1 (Box 68)
      The episode includes: Namibia prepares for elections; former South African police officer confesses to hit squad killings; Zimbabwe in its tenth year of independence; video premiere of Zimbabwe's Thomas Mapfumo.
    - Episode N203, 1989 November 15; 1 (Box 69)
      The episode includes: SWAPO wins Namibia elections; exclusive interview with Albertina Sisulu in New York; South Africa lures East German refugees after Berlin Wall comes down; Liverpool dockworkers institute blockade of Namibian uranium exports.
      General
      This cassette also contains a copy of N202.
    - Episode N204, 1989 November 22; 1 (Box 70)
      The episode includes: SWAPO victory in Namibia, post-election analysis; former South African police captain confesses to hit squad killings; the American Committee on Africa; Italian artists against apartheid.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 70D)
    - Episode N205, 1989 November 29; 1 (Box 71)
      The episode includes: Namibian constituent assembly meets for first time; church meeting headed by Walter Sisulu attacked by police; white South African draft resister denied political asylum in United States; Canadian-South African trade.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 71D)
    - Episode N206, 1989 December 6; 1 (Box 72)
      The episode includes: the South African press ban, has it worked?; South African police detective is held in killings of David Webster and Anton Lubowski; author Kurt Vonnegut visits Mozambique and assesses the effects of the guerilla war; anti-apartheid holiday gifts.
      - Duplicating master for N206 and N207, 1 (Box 72D)
    - Episode N207, 1989 December 13; 1 (Box 73)
      The episode includes: December 9 "Conference for a Democratic Future" held in South Africa; recent violence in Natal Province covered up by Pretoria; Randall Robinson commentary: has McCarthyism returned, spotlight on new media blacklists; the South African military weapons industry.
      - Duplicating master for N206 and N207, 1 (Box 72D)
    - Episode N208, 1989 December 21; 1 (Box 74)
      The episode includes: review of top ten news stories from Southern Africa in 1989.
      - Duplicating master for N208 and N209, 1 (Box 74D)
    - Episode N209, 1989 December 27; 1 (Box 75)
      The episode includes: holiday music special featuring music from and about Southern Africa; rock and rap against apartheid, music from Southern Africa; history of anti-apartheid anthem God Bless Africa.
      - Duplicating master for N208 and N209, 1 (Box 74D)
    - Episode N210, 1990 January 4; 1 (Box 76)
      The episode includes: preacher power special edition; Reverend Allan Boesak speaks to the United Nations Special Session on apartheid, 12/89; Archbishop Trevor Huddleston, excerpt from International Defence and Aid Fund (IDAF) documentary.
      - Duplicating master for N210, N211, and N212, 1 (Box 76D)
    - Episode N211, 1990 January 11; 1 (Box 77)
      The episode includes: exclusive interview with Archbishop Desmond Tutu about his remarks on Israel and the Holocaust; Mandela family Christmas visit, release rumors; Pik (R. F.) Botha visits Hungary; Athol Fugard, South African playwright.
      - Duplicating master for N210, N211, and N212, 1 (Box 76D)
    - Episode N212, 1990 January 17; 1 (Box 78)
      The episode includes: exclusive interview with Winnie Mandela; South Africa's failed educational system; Congressman Howard Wolpe meets with De Klerk and calls for tougher sanctions; exiled South African jazz singer Sathima Bea Benjamin.
      - Duplicating master for N210, N211, and N212, 1 (Box 76D)
    - Episode N213, 1990 January 24; 1 (Box 79)
      The episode includes: suspended South Africa police lieutenant Gregory Rockman speaks out further against apartheid and police violence; Natal and the unreported war; the United Democratic Front unbans itself; profile of South African jazz musician Hugh Masekela.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 79D)
  - Third Season (National)
    - Episode N301, 1990 January 31; 1 (Box 80)
      The episode includes: the world press waits for Mandela: the latest details and concerns about media commitment; interview with the editor, Max Du Preez, and reporter, Jacques Pauw, of the newspaper, Vrye Weekblad, which first broke the story about South African hit squads; South African photographer Peter Magubane.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 80D)
    - Episode N302, 1990 February 7; 1 (Box 81)
      The episode includes: South Africa parliament unbans the ANC and announces freedom for Mandela; ambassadress of song, South African Mama Abriga.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 81D)
    - Episode N303, 1990 February 14; 1 (Box 82)
      The episode includes: freedom day, Nelson Mandela's walk to freedom; coverage of Mandela's return to Soweto, his speech, the celebration and first press conference; analysis of Mandela's historic address in Capetown.
    - Episode N304, 1990 February 21; 1 (Box 83)
      The episode includes: first television interview with Zwelakhe Sisulu, editor of the New Nation; New York celebration of Mandela's release; youth leadership, featuring interview with Peter Mokabe, president of the South African Youth Congress; interview with Rian Malan, author of My Traitor's Heart.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 83D)
    - Episode N305, 1990 February 28; 1 (Box 84)
      The episode includes: part I of the Nelson Mandela interview conducted by Allister Sparks; Nelson Mandela's visit to Lusaka; clips of Nelson Mandela's address in Durban asking for peace with Inkatha; review of Survival, a play about South African prison life, starring South Africa Now 's Fana Kekana.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 84D)
    - Episode N306, 1990 March 7; 1 (Box 85)
      The episode includes: Mandela goes to Lusaka and meets with his old comrades; part II of the Nelson Mandela interview conducted by Allister Sparks; Elonga, one of the most popular bands in Zimbabwe.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 85D)
    - Episode N307, 1990 March 14; 1 (Box 86)
      The episode includes: ANC conference in Lusaka, Zambia; coverage of Mandela's trip to Zimbabwe, Tanzania and Sweden; report on death squads in South Africa including an interview with Dirk Coetzee, former hit squad commander; art exhibition, Women from South Africa.
    - Episode N308, 1990 March 21; 1 (Box 87)
      The episode includes: Namibia's road to freedom; reunion of Nelson Mandela and Oliver Tambo in Sweden; the sounds of the Bhundu Boys from Zimbabwe.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 87D)
    - Episode N309, 1990 March 28; 1 (Box 88)
      The episode includes: Namibian independence celebration; covering the coverage: interview with NBC's Tom Brokaw; communism at a crossroad: interview with Communist Party General Secretary Joe Slovo; sounds of Namibia: the first music video by a Namibian musician, Nathan Ndjiharine.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 88D)
    - Episode N310, 1990 April 4; 1 (Box 89)
      The episode includes: violence in the South African township of Sebokeng and in the Natal region; investigative report on toxic waste dumping in South Africa by United States company, American Cyanamid; dancing by Shaka Zulu, the new generation.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 89D)
    - Episode N311, 1990 April 11; 1 (Box 90)
      The episode includes: Natal's civil war and Sebokeng police massacre; ANC's future plans; South African homelands; report on South African shebeens.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 90D)
    - Episode N312, 1990 April 18; 1 (Box 91)
      The episode includes: Mandela concert at Wembley Stadium, a concert Americans did not get to see; update on Natal's civil war; protest of American Cyanamid plant in New Jersey for dumping toxic waste in South Africa; interview with Beyers Naudé, an Afrikaner and active opponent of apartheid; tribute to Harry Belafonte.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 91D)
    - Episode N313, 1990 April 25; 1 (Box 92)
      The episode includes: Namibia joins the United Nations as its 160th member state; labor watch: report on the Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU); highlights of the Mandela concert at Wembley Stadium in London.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 92D)
  - Fourth Season (National)
    - Episode N401, 1990 May 2; 1 (Box 93)
      The episode includes: negotiation process between the ANC and the South African government; Natal Province update; oil and apartheid; review of The Gods Must be Crazy II.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 93D)
    - Episode N402, 1990 May 9; 1 (Box 94)
      The episode includes: the government and the ANC start the process of negotiations; interview with the First Lady of Mozambique, Grac?a Machel; M.I.T. divestment protests; the American rap group, Stetsasonic, at Wembley and their video, A.F.R.I.C.A. about Southern Africa.
    - Episode N403, 1990 May 16; 1 (Box 95)
      The episode includes: letter bomb sent to anti-apartheid activist and ANC supporter, Father Michael Lapsley, in Zimbabwe; viruses exported to South Africa's Institute for Virology from the Centers for Disease Control; "Street to Struggle," the street children of South Africa; the role of culture in the liberation struggle, interview with Albie Sachs.
    - Episode N404, 1990 May 23; 1 (Box 96)
      The episode includes: white extremists attack South African blacks as Afrikaaner resistance movement issues call to arms; South African President F.W. De Klerk visits Belgium, Germany and London; executive encourages Fortune 500's to make a stand against apartheid; Voices From South Africa, an exhibit of contemporary art by South African exiles, is on national tour.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 96D)
    - Episode N405, 1990 May 30; 1 (Box 97)
      The episode includes: South African President F.W. De Klerk cancels United States visit after successful European tour; national guardsmen massacre 150 students in Zaire; more blacks appear in South African television advertisements; South African diamonds defy international trade sanctions; music video premiere, Gimme Hope Jo'anna, by Eddy Grant.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 97D)
    - Episode N406, 1990 June 6; 1 (Box 98)
      The episode includes: South African leader Nelson Mandela's upcoming United States visit; South African Defense Force delegation meets with ANC military representatives; Black women domestic workers continue efforts to organize; Chimurenga music by Zimbabwean star Thomas Mapfumo.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 98D)
    - Episode N407, 1990 June 13; 1 (Box 99)
      The episode includes: state of emergency lifted in three of South Africa's four provinces; Mandela tours Europe to bolster sanctions before coming to the United States; Soweto Day, June 16, 1976, the student uprising remembered; music video world premiere, Freedom Charter, by Michael Edward-Stevens.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 99D)
    - Episode N408, 1990 June 20; 1 (Box 100)
      The episode includes: Nelson and Winnie Mandela make history as they arrive in New York; Mayor Dinkins and the entire city honor Mandela with a ticker tape parade; behind-the-scenes look at the preparation for Mandela's visit; controversy over the disclosure that the CIA may have helped capture Mandela in 1962; a look at local efforts to tighten sanctions against Pretoria.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 100D)
    - Episode N409, 1990 June 27; 1 (Box 101)
      The episode includes: in the second week of the ANC leader's visit, Nelson Mandela prepares to address Congress; Winnie Mandela describes the suffering of black women under apartheid; Mandela delivers his message: keep the pressure on the South African government; Yankee Stadium is sold out as New York honors the Mandelas with a musical tribute.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 101D)
    - Episode N410, 1990 July 4; 1 (Box 102)
      The episode includes: Mandela's world tour hailed as a tremendous success as the ANC leader returns home; a coup attempt against President Kenneth Kaunda of Zambia stirs that nation; effects of the ongoing conflict on the children of Natal Province; Artists United Against Apartheid honor Mandela at Robert De Niro's Tribeca Grill.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 102D)
    - Episode N411, 1990 July 11; 1 (Box 103)
      The episode includes: a white supremacy group takes responsibility for the bombing of Vrye Weekblad newspaper; United States religious leaders meet with black South African leaders during a fact-finding mission; workers stage a massive strike to protest violence in Natal Province; Soweto Teachers' Choir.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 103D)
    - Episode N412, 1990 July 18; 1 (Box 104)
      The episode includes: United States Customs sting operation uncovers international scheme to route arms to South Africa; New York expands South African sanctions bill making it the toughest in the country; American Cyanamid's toxic wastes contaminate South African river; painters and sculptors from South Africa's townships.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 104D)
    - Episode N413, 1990 July 25; 1 (Box 105)
      The episode includes: rock against apartheid, Peter Gabriel, Bruce Springsteen, Miles Davis; Mzwakhe Mbuli, the people's poet; rappin' against apartheid, Queen Latifah, Stetsasonic, Brother music videos; Mahlathini and the Mahotella Queens music video.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 105D)
  - Fifth Season (National)
    - Episode N501, 1990 August 1; 1 (Box 106)
      The episode includes: Yankee Stadium concert in honor of Nelson and Winnie Mandela; Eddy Grant's Gimme Hope Jo'anna and Phranc's Bloodbath music videos; Miriam Makeba interview and Ms. Makeba performs Welela music video; Freedom Charter, Michael Edward-Stevens' new video.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 106D)
    - Episode N502, 1990 August 8; 1 (Box 107)
      The episode includes: political alliance between the South African Communist Party and the ANC examined; plot to overthrow Namibia's government uncovered; former police captain, Dirk Coetzee, talks about South African hit squads; the work of Peter Magubane, black South African photographer.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 107D)
    - Episode N503, 1990 August 15; 1 (Box 108)